德罗纳实际上想教训木柱王
Dronacharya, in reality wanted
to teach Drupada, you know,
甚至是
that even being
这样一个伟大的国王 你也会轻视你的友谊
such a great king you
disvalue your friendship.
另一方面 如果你知道木柱王和德罗纳的故事
In another part, you see, if you know
the story of Drupada and Dronacharya,
你会看到 在德罗纳的头脑中
you will see that in
the mind of Dronacharya,
他并不自由
he was not free.
在他的头脑中 他仍然执着于
In his mind, he
was still attached
想要教训木柱王这一想法
and due to wanted to
teach the lesson to Drupada,
他想要获得最杰出的箭术
you see, he wanted to have the
best of all archery, you know.
所以 在教训他(木柱王)的过程中
So, he wanted to
have the best archer
他想用最好的箭手
in the process
to teach him the lesson.
所以 那份贪婪在那
So, that greed was there,
想要更多的贪婪
the greed of wanting
more and more.
同时木柱王
And in Drupada,
即使他是 如何来形容
even if he was in
– how you call it –
无知
ignorance,
他很自信
you see, he had faith.
他不知道发生了什么
He didn’t know what was
happening to him, you know,
因为当你无知时
because when
you are in ignorance,
你不知道发生了什么 你轻视了你的友谊
you don’t know what is happening
to you. You disvalue your friendship,
你变得傲慢 你变得
you become arrogant,
you become
虚伪等等 不是吗
hypocrite and so on, no?
但是德罗纳本应该从最佳的位置
But Dronacharya should
have been in the best position
去纠正这些 对吗
to rectify that, no?
但是德罗纳没有去做
But Dronacharya didn’t.
所以 那就是为什么在那故事里
So, that’s why in that story
他表现出贪婪 并且也因为那贪婪他甚至不能
he represents that greed and also
due to that greed he could not even,
当黑公主在宫廷中被羞辱时 他也没有
when Draupadi was insulted
in the court, he could not
起身和保护黑公主
get up and defend
Draupadi also.
那阻住了他
That stopped him.
你瞧 人生中有很多美好的事物
You see, there are many
fine things, you see,
常常流经发生
which often go
through life.
一些人吵架 然后下一刻他们又成了最好的朋友
Somebody can shout and the next
moment they are again your best friend.
他们忘得非常快 是不是
They forget very
quickly. Isn’t it?
然而 有一些人吵架
Whereas, there are some
people who can shout,
可是 他们将怨恨记在了心里
but yet, they keep
the grudge inside.
这就是德罗纳的性格
And this was the
character of Dronacharya.
并且这一点在他死之前
And this was reminded
to him by Krishna
奎师那也提醒了 那就是为什么他和持国百子在一起
before he died. That’s why
he was with the Kauravas.
他没有和般度五子在一起 否则 那会是截然不同的
He was not with the Pandavas.
Otherwise, it would have been vice versa.
因为他内在的贪欲 他去了那里
Due to that greediness
inside of him, he was there.
所以 那就是为什么在这个故事里 他表现出那永不满足的贪婪
So, that’s why in this story he represents
that greed of never being satisfied,
永远不够
never being enough.
这就是贪婪的品质 当你贪婪于某些东西
This is the quality of greed, you know.
When you have greed for something,
你永远不会满足于你所拥有的
you are never satisfied
with what you have.